[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
[Music]
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
thank you
for connecting with us
hope you are doing well
let's start our today's session
through this video we will learn about
the overview of tosca as a test
automation tool
before starting the tutorial we should
have prerequisites knowledge on software
testing for better understanding
[Music]
all right
let's starts with the concepts of
automation testing
automation testing is an approach to
perform the manual test steps
automatically by test tools or robots
the main goals of test automation is to
ensure the quality of software products
through the automation
save the human efforts
and reduces the software development
life cycle
[Music]
nowadays the i t industry demands the
quality and the efficacy with minimum
human efforts to deliver any i t
services
here automation testing is playing a big
role for testing services
[Music]
automation testing is an approach to
automate the testing process to reduce
the human efforts
in the automation testing services the
tools like qtp uft rft and selenium were
very famous
tosca is best suited tool as it supports
the script less testing which will
consume minimum time to learn
tosca user can write efficient test
cases with minimum skill set
also it generates a standard test
reports for the management without any
customization apart from these reasons
there is other advantages as well which
we will learn later
there is lots of automation tools are
available in the market
but why are we talking about tosca
let's understand the reasons behind this
tosca is one of the market leading tool
in the present days
it has the ability to perform functional
and regression testing as well
the api testing can be done through
tosca which has an important role in
agile process
all right
now we will discuss about the important
features of tosca which has changed the
dimension of automation in testing
spaces
the features are mostly used to define
the strategy of test automation
development execution and maintenance
activities
also it helps for management reporting
as well
[Music]
model based testing approach is the most
important feature of tosca which makes
it as a market leader in testing domain
as a part of test case development
testers need to create modules for each
of the unit level functionalities or
activities
the modules contain the technical
information to automate functional test
steps
to develop the test cases we need to
combine modules
the another important aspect of tosca as
it supports the risk-based testing
approach
which means tosca is capable of assess
the risk with the test cases
[Music]
basically it can identify the subset of
entire test suite which will minimize
the chances of risks
once the execution is completed risks
are measured by considering the
automated test execution result and the
risk coverage
tosca supports script less automation
which means that test cases can be
developed by drag and drop method of
modules
also the test data parameterization and
the implementations of verification
steps can be done through the
configurations
so anyone will be able to develop test
cases with minimum skill set and
training
it helps to develop test cases in
shorter span of time
distribution execution signifies about
the distribution of test execution in
multiple systems to reduce the human
efforts and execution cycle time
based on the configuration of
distributed execution we can schedule
the test execution in multiple systems
in an unattended mode
[Music]
also tosca can be easily integrated with
third-party ci tools such as jenkins
azure devops jira etc
the other important features are
dynamic test data can be handled through
the task of features such as tcd tdm and
tds
test recording features allows tester to
record and create the test scenarios by
single click
tosca is compatible with most of the
applications such as salesforce sap web
powerbuilder.net
mainframe mobile devices
api testing is very useful and the
entire application is not ready but some
of the application components are
developed
using the api tosca is able to test the
corresponding application components by
following simple steps
tosca helps to integrate with
third-party tools with minimum
customization such as perfecto selenium
q-test to enhance the scope of
automation testing
let's understand the high level
architecture of tosca
the tool is developed with five
different components
tosca commander is used to manage the
test automation activities such as
development execution maintenance and
reporting
tosca scan wizard component allows
tester to scan the test application and
create modules
scanning is used to capture technical
information of aut
[Music]
tosca executive manages the test
executions and test logs
the test repository is used to store the
test cases modules dynamic test data
user information etc in a shared
repository
the different databases like oracle
skill server db2 are used for this
purpose
license server manages to configure
connect and validate the licenses for
users to access tosca
tosca is designed and developed by
trisentis
the tool can be accessed through
different user interfaces such as
gui the graphical user interface
provides a graphical looks for the user
api application programming interface
cl command line interface n
accessed via integrated test management
environment
thanks for watching this video
that's all about tosca overview topic
we will learn more about tosca's setup
and configurations in next tosca
tutorial
please visit our website lambdageeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain
you can check our other website as well
[Music]
we have features like youtube trends
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
[Music]
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query